<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Peter Jones - Home</title>
    <link>https://PeterJonesProjects.github.io/PeterJonesPortfolio/tags/MSc%20Data%20Science%20(Statistics)/</link>
    <description>MSc Projects on Peter Jones - Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 11:15:58 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://PeterJonesProjects.github.io/PeterJonesPortfolio/tags/MSc%20Data%20Science%20(Statistics)/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Time Series Analysis &amp; Forecasting of Monthly Product Sales</title>
      <link>https://PeterJonesProjects.github.io/PeterJonesPortfolio/post/proj5.time-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://PeterJonesProjects.github.io/PeterJonesPortfolio/post/proj5.time-series/</guid>
      <description>This project aimed to analyze and forecast monthly sales data for a product over a period of ten years. The primary goal was to identify the best statistical model for predicting future sales, based on the historical sales data. The project also included solving two mathematical questions related to time series theory, which added an academic component to the project.
The project utilized the R programming language, specifically the dlm library, to perform the data analysis and modeling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classification of Breast Tissue Samples using Statistical Methods</title>
      <link>https://PeterJonesProjects.github.io/PeterJonesPortfolio/post/proj3.breastcancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://PeterJonesProjects.github.io/PeterJonesPortfolio/post/proj3.breastcancer/</guid>
      <description>In this project, I aimed to develop classifiers for predicting cancer presence in breast tissue samples using cytological characteristics data. To achieve this objective, I employed statistical methods such as logistic regression and linear discriminant analysis (LDA) to build multiple classifiers. The evaluation of these classifiers was done through cross-validation to compare their performance. I used the R programming language and major libraries such as bestglm, glmnet, and MASS to develop these classifiers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Application of Learning Analytics to &#39;Massive Online Open Course&#39; Data</title>
      <link>https://PeterJonesProjects.github.io/PeterJonesPortfolio/post/proj4.learnanalytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://PeterJonesProjects.github.io/PeterJonesPortfolio/post/proj4.learnanalytics/</guid>
      <description>The project discussed here involved applying learning analytics to the data collected from multiple runs of a Massive Open Online Course (MOOC). The aim was to gain insights that could help course providers make improvements to the course content and delivery. The project followed the CRISP-DM process for data mining, which involves a cyclical approach to data analysis that includes six phases: business understanding, data understanding, data preparation, modeling, evaluation, and deployment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian infernce project (Open Project)</title>
      <link>https://PeterJonesProjects.github.io/PeterJonesPortfolio/post/proj7.bayes-proj/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://PeterJonesProjects.github.io/PeterJonesPortfolio/post/proj7.bayes-proj/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
